

Diogo Trindade Basto

CONTACT

Porto Portugal E-mail: diogotbasto@gmail.com
Website: http://misirlou.github.io/

Phone: +351 914033198

SUMMARY

FEUP graduate with a master's in software engineering. Programming since tenth grade, starting with Pascal, moving to C, SQL, VB.Net during high school and many more along university, including Java, PHP and C#. Learned technologies outside the curriculum like Node.JS and Python.

Software engineer with 2 year experience developing PHP web applications with multiple frameworks. Experience with MySQL databases, PHPUnit and CircleCl for testing, RabbitMQ for messaging, Amazon Web Services for cloud deployment, Ansible for infrastructure, Docker and Vagrant for development environments. Worked with scrumming and code reviewing practices.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AdClick

Developer

February 2017 - August 2017

In February I moved from Smarkio to the parent company AdClick to assist with the infrastructure move from Amazon Web Services to Microsoft Azure, with the secondary purpose of coding our own infrastructure with **Ansible** and **Terraform**. The company worked with the same core technologies as Smarkio (**PHP** and **MySQL**) but the lack of a dedicated operations team meant that development team spent half of the time keeping up with publishing platform problems and new advertising pages instead of focusing in infrastructure move or using new technology to solve our problems better. I got to take development ownership of one of the most profitable products in the company, suggesting several new features to the business team that increased their productivity and planning the infrastructure change for the project that took zero downtime. With this change we also switched our database servers to **Percona**, providing additional performance enhancements and monitoring tools for our databases.

Smarkio June 2016 - January 2017

Full-Stack Web Developer

At Smarkio we worked mostly with **PHP** with the **Symphony** framework and a **MySQL** database but it gave me an amazing opportunity to expand my experience and grow beyond just those technologies. From writing **PHPUnit** tests, using and configuring a **CircleCI**, to migrating the development environment from **Vagrant** to **Docker**. Implementing **Vue.JS** frontend in pages that were redesigned. Managing and monitoring **RabbitMQ**.

On the managing side of things, the team worked with the scrum methodology backed up by a **JIRA** board, ensuring work was properly peer reviewed and tested before being deployed.

Diogo Trindade Basto

Brandmeup May 2014 - October 2014

Web Developer

Developer of an online platform MVP with **CakePHP** and **MySQL** for professional networking. The web and database infrastructure was also under my responsibility.

NIAEFEUP

September 2013 - February 2015

Member

Member of a students' association branch, developing small projects and ideas on our free time. As a member I led the Timetable Selector project and contributed to other projects like Kommando (a game that used a Microsoft Kinect) and UNI, helped organize the yearly student association lan party and manage our internal network and servers.

EDUCATION

Master's in Informatics and Computing Engineering

September 2009 - February 2015

Faculty of Engineering of University of Porto

As a student I enjoyed most of the master's vast curriculum and even picked up a few more technologies myself. Among the several projects I worked for the course, these stand out the most:

- Guess me out: Ruby on Rails website that allowed dynamic avatar creation and matching different users to play against each other a game like "Guess who?".
- Pay as you Go: ASP.Net website for a proof-of-concept system that allows insurance companies to register driver information through GPS systems and perform simulations and premium calculation using the new parameters.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native

English: Full working proficiency

OTHER Experiences

- C#: Peer to peer video chat application; Airport landing strip scheduling algorithm; Model and controller code for an ASP.NET MVC website (Pay as you go).
- OpenGL: Used the framework with C++ to generate scenes defined in XML files, including animations and shaders.
- Blender: Used with python to make a graphical simulation of a robot interacting with a user controlled actor.
- Parallel Programming: Programming in C++ for multiple cores with OpenMP and distributed computing with MPI.
- LaTeX: Wrote my thesis in LaTex and managed references with BibTeX.

INTERESTS

Parallel Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Networking, Algorithms and Open-source.

On my free time I enjoy playing electric guitar, computer games, dungeons and dragons and watching TV shows.

Diogo Trindade Basto 2